Shishir Chandra

Address: C-803, Callisto, Wakad, Pune-411057

Mobile: +91 9764591411 e-mail: chandrashishir@yahoo.com

Experience and Skills Summary

MBA, CISA, BS 7799 LA having total of 13+ years of experience in IT and Information Security.

9+ years of experience in Information Systems (IS) Security Consulting, Audits & Operations.

Key Skills in Information Security:

- 1. Information security risk management.
- 2. Establishing information security governance framework.
- 3. Information security program and project management.
- 4. Delivering information security contractual and compliance requirements.
- 5. Information systems & security Audits.
- 6. Information systems & security consulting (e.g. ISO 27001, SAS 70, HIPAA, PCI-DSS)
- 7. Enterprise Risk Management (ERM)
- 8. Preparing and reviewing proposals, reports, dashboard and status updates.
- 9. Preparing and reviewing contracts, security schedules and exhibits.

Presently working as APAC IT Security Lead (part of the global IT security team) with Global Process Services (GPS) division of **IBM**. Present responsibilities include providing IT security consulting, guidance, support, and assistance to IBM's operating units delivering services to multiple customers across the globe. Prior to that, worked as the Security Operations Lead of the Security & Risk Management (SRM) Tower of Information Technology Delivery (ITD) division of **IBM** with one of its major strategic outsourcing telecom clients. Major responsibilities included delivering all aspects of information security & compliance requirements and implementation of enterprise wide security solutions/projects. Prior to that worked as Manager with **Deloitte** Touche Tohmatsu India (P) Ltd. ('Deloitte') - Enterprise Risk Services (ERS) Practice. Delivered multiple information security consulting projects on SOX, Clause 49, ISO 27001, SAS 70, Enterprise Risk Management (ERM), Identity Management, Vulnerability Management along with Application Security audits for ERP implementations based on SAP, Oracle & MFG Pro platforms in multiple countries for Global Organizations. Before that, I was working with Stratin Infoserve (P) Ltd. as Consultant & Project Manager - Security Consulting Practice. Job responsibilities included IS consulting, IS audit, BS7799 implementation project management & execution and key account management.

Educational Qualifications

MBA ISM, Dhanbad (1999)

• B.Com Patna University, Patna (1995)

Professional Certifications

- Certified Information Systems Auditor (CISA)
- Certified BS 7799 Lead Auditor

Technical Skills

- Information Systems & Security Operations, Consulting and Audit.
- ISO 27001, SAS 70, HIPAA, PCI-DSS Consulting, Implementation and Audit.
- Vulnerability Assessment and Penetration Testing.
- Information security risk assessment, mitigation and monitoring.
- Conducting onsite and remote information security reviews.
- Developing and implementing information security policies, procedures and standards.
- Experienced in multiple OS (Unix, Linux, AIX, Solaris, Windows), DB (Oracle, MS-SQL) and networking devices (Firewall, IDS, Routers etc)
- Preparing technical proposals / RFP responses.
- Preparing, reviewing and presenting proposals, reports, dashboard and status updates.
- Reviewing contracts, security schedules and exhibits.

Professional Work Experience

Presently working with...

1. IBM India (P) Ltd. (Duration: January 2009 to till date)

1. (a) IBM - Global Process Services, Pune

Designation: APAC IT Security Lead (Part of global IT security team)

Duration: August 2010 to till date

IBM Global Process Services (GPS) combines business, industry and process knowledge with supporting technologies. These services and solutions help bring strategic and comprehensive management of a variety of business processes, including CRM, HR, F&A, and key industry verticals. These services are provided from shared delivery centers in Manila, Budapest, Krakow etc using various IBM and vendor applications.

Working as APAC IT Security lead, I am responsible for providing consulting, guidance, support, and assistance to IBM's operating units delivering process outsourcing services. These include activities ranging from pre-sales support, new account transition and support to steady state accounts. Some of the key deliverables include supporting sales team for finalizing security and compliance requirements, transitioning the accounts to IBM security standards/contractual requirements, meeting contractual obligations, evaluating and recommending security controls, conducting contract reviews, internal audits and managing external audits etc.

IT/Security Risk Assessment and Audits

Responsible for performing Risk Assessment and conducting onsite/offsite audits of IBM global delivery centers.

IT infrastructure security

Responsible to ensure that IT infrastructure components are managed as per IBM internal security standards and, if applicable, specific contractual requirements. Responsible for establishing, and where applicable, improving information security governance framework. Activities include regular meetings, reviews and compliance testing. Any deviations are identified, reported and tracked to closure.

Application security

Responsibilities include preparation of application security baseline to include the minimum set of mandatory controls to be implemented and conducting periodic reviews to ensure compliance.

Review of new solutions

Responsibilities include review of all new proposals and customer specific security requirements (including compliance/best practices like HIPAA, PCI-DSS, ISO 27001 etc) for finalizing security deliverables. This includes end to end solution review and identification of security requirements over and above IBM internal standards and assisting the solution architects in adjusting the costing and implementation timelines accordingly.

Audit Support

Providing support for customer initiated audits including audit of general computer controls, infrastructure and application audits.

Contract review

Review of existing contract for identifying any unfulfilled requirement and tracking the deviations to closure.

Internal consultancy to different delivery centers

Supporting different accounts teams in variety of matters related to IT security. This include guidance on any update to security documents, implementation of controls to meet compliance requirements (e.g. PCI-DSS, HIPAA) for specific accounts and implementation of the same etc.

Reporting/Status Updates

Preparing reports and presenting findings/status to IBM and/or customer management. Include account/delivery center/business unit level reports, dashboards, progress on issue closure etc.

1. (b) IBM India (P) Ltd, - Integrated Technology Delivery, Pune

Designation: Security Operations Lead – Security & Risk Management (SRM)

Duration: January 2009 to July 2010

Integrated Technology Delivery (ITD) is a key element of IBM's globally integrated capability. ITD provides complete outsourcing of IT infrastructure management and support services to its customers.

I was the Security Operations Lead for SRM team for a major telecom account to deliver all information security & compliance requirements. Leading a team 30+ information security resources and responsibilities include managing information security operations, multiple project implementation & ongoing compliance to various IS processes & procedures and also to different internal & external frameworks.

Information security operations

IS Program Management: Responsible for managing different IS programs PAN India and establishing information security governance framework. Include Vulnerability, Patch, Anti-virus, Security Incident, Service Activation & Deactivation, Security Health Check Management, UserID Management etc.

IS Risk Management: Responsible for conducting periodic information security risk assessment, risk mitigation and management to determine the effectiveness of implemented controls and taking corrective actions if required.

IS Project Management: Responsible for evaluating & selecting IS solutions and ensuring end-to-end implementation.

- 1. Managed the establishment of SOC (Security Operations Center) based on RSA Envision Solution and Guardium database monitoring
- 2. Successfully managed and delivered multiple IS projects (e.g. AV consolidations, RSA Authentication / token, Websense Content Filtering etc)

Application Security:

Responsible for setting up the Application Security Vertical within the account. This includes recruitment of resources, developing & implementing appsec processes and establishing baseline.

Compliance:

Facilitated PCI-DSS certification (first Telecom in India). Also, supported in various regulatory audits (SOX/SAS 70), certifications (e.g. ISO 27001) as well as IBM internal audits.

Information Security product and solution evaluation/POC/selection:

Leadership role in evaluating and selection of different security solutions including POC and ensuring buy-in from various stakeholders. Example includes SOC, DB logging etc.

Reporting:

Responsible for meeting various reporting requirements for

- 1. IBM's top management (Account, AP, Global level)
- 2. Compliance (SOX/SAS 70 reports/dashboards at predefined frequency e.g. daily, weekly, monthly) and
- 3. Customer top management (Project, Security, Compliance status update / snapshot)

Team Management:

- 1. Managing a team of 30+ resources
- 2. Responsible for training, recruitment and growth of team members

2. Deloitte Touche Tohmatsu India (P) Ltd., New Delhi (www.deloitte.com)

Designation: Manager – Enterprise Risk Services (ERS)

Duration: September 2006 – December 2008

Deloitte is one of the Big 4 consulting & auditing firms. Its ERS division is providing specialized services related to enterprise risk management and information systems security.

Part of the core consulting team in a leadership role in the Information Security domain including VA / PT, Identity Management and Compliance consulting. I have successfully managed & executed number of onsite IS / IT Audits and Consulting projects in India and abroad. Some of the projects I have worked on are mentioned below:

Vulnerability Assessment & Penetration Testing

Key member of the national practice for carrying out VA/PT projects and delivered several project. **Project:** Conducting onsite VA/PT for one of the biggest HR recruitment firms of the world having offices in multiple countries. I was involved in the execution of this project in three countries.

Location: Bangalore (India), Taipei (Taiwan), Melbourne (Australia)

Role: Onsite Consultant and manager for carrying out vulnerability assessment and penetration testing using various open source & commercial tools and proprietary scripts. It also involved helping in the remediation efforts of the client to achieve various compliance requirements / baseline.

IS Security & Compliance Consulting

I have worked on multiple assignments including ISO 27001, SAS 70, Clause 49 etc helping clients achieve compliance / regulatory requirements. My role was executing and managing projects and teams for meeting project goals and also providing specialized technical and process improvement / reengineering consultancy.

IS / IT Audit

I have led multiple IT audit projects for clients operating in different verticals and having diverse IT infrastructure like SAP, MFG-Pro, Oracle on different flavors of Unix (Red Hat Linux, AIX, Solaris) / Windows (2000 / 2003) and having Oracle, SQL Server as backend database. These audits were conducted to provide reasonable assurance on the effectiveness of internal controls to our financial audit team and also include providing detailed recommendations for remediation.

Establishment of Enterprise Risk Management (ERM) Framework

I am part of the core team providing ERM services as mandated in the Corporate Governance requirements of different regulations like Clause 49 and also the guidelines issued by the Planning Commission for the CPSE. Responsibilities include consultancy, conducting interviews of the top management, facilitating workshops, reporting and project management.

3. Stratin Infoserve Pvt. Ltd., New Delhi (www.stratin-consulting.com)

Designation: Project Manager & Consultant – Security Consulting Practice

Duration: April 2004 – September 2006

This is a software development and consulting firm providing focussed services and consulting in the area of Information Security, BS 7799 Certification and IS Audit to reputed firms in India. This is also a consulting & implementation partner of Computer Associates (CA) for its enterprise suites related to infrastructure management and security information management (SIM).

I was associated with this company in a techno – managerial capacity as a Project Manager & Consultant–Security Consulting. I had been involved in strategic planning, consulting, project management, preparation of technical presentations and technical tender bid documents etc. Some of the projects I have worked on is provided below:

Project 1: Implementation of BS 7799 based ISMS for a major PSU in the Power sector

Project 2: Internal IS/IT Audit for a major telecom company (Bharti-Airtel)

Project 3: Setting up the inhouse Computer Associates (CA) technology lab

4. Summary of 4+ years of experience in Project Management & Software Development.

Worked as Project Manager & Key Account Manager with Software Technology Group International Ltd. (STG) as Manager – Banking Division in implementation and customization of Finacle in PNB, UBI etc. Prior to that worked with Stratin Infoserve (P) Ltd., as Team Leader - Security Division for information security projects including VA/PT and system hardening and preparing configuration baseline documents for OS, DB and network devices. Also worked with e - Inforogers (P) Ltd. (www.criccontest.com) as Project Leader handling software development.

Personal Details

Personal Details
39 years (DOB: 06-Sep-1974), Male, Married, Indian.

Passport Number G7348604